Inventory of the Allen Weinstein papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Allen Weinstein papers
1948-2004
2004C61
Hoover Institution Archives
169 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 2 oversize boxes (71.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, conference proceedings, printed matter, photocopies of government documents, and sound recordings relating to promotion of democratic institutions outside the United States; to Soviet espionage in the United States, especially the cases of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg and Alger Hiss; and to the attempted assassination of Pope John Paul II. Includes research material used for the books by Allen Weinstein, Perjury: The Hiss-Chambers Case (New York, 1978) and The Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in America (New York, 1999).
Weinstein, Allen.
Access
Boxes 121-148 are closed. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004, with increments received in subsequent years.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Material
Center for Democracy records, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1937 September 1 Born, New York City
1967 PhD, Yale University
1966-1981 Professor of history, Smith College, Northampton, Massachusetts
1970 Author, Prelude to Populism
1978 Author, Perjury: The Hiss-Chambers Case
1981-1983 Professor of history, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C.
1982-1983 Executive director, The Democracy Program, Washington, D.C. Executive editor, The Washington Quarterly
1984 President, Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions
1985-1989 Professor of history, Boston University
1985-2003 Founder and president, Center for Democracy, Washington, D.C.
1999 Co-author, The Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in America—The Stalin Era
2002 Author, The Story of America: Freedom and Crisis from Settlement to Superpower
2005-2008 Archivist of the United States, Washington, D.C.
2015 June 18 Died, Gaithersburg, Maryland
Scope and Content of Collection
Acquired in 2004, the Allen Weinstein papers in the Hoover Institution Archives span much of the career of an important American historian who had also long been involved in the arena of public policy. Consisting of correspondence, writings, conference proceedings, printed matter, and some sound recordings, the papers largely relate to American domestic and foreign policy, with additional significant materials relating to Soviet espionage in the United States before and during World War II.
Of particular interest to historians are the extensive research materials in the papers pertaining to the books Perjury: The Hiss-Chambers Case and The Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in America—The Stalin Era. These include a large number of photocopies of FBI and other files which were obtained by Weinstein under the Freedom of Information Act. The research materials also include a large number of clippings and other printed matter, as well as interviews conducted by Weinstein of numerous individuals associated with the Hiss case, including Alger Hiss himself. There are also microfilm reels containing documents relating to the purported involvement of Bulgarian security forces in the attempted assassination of Pope John Paul II in 1981.
The papers also include materials relating to Weinstein's editorship of The Washington Quarterly in the 1980s and his tenure as executive director of The Democracy Program and its successor organization, the National Endowment for Democracy, from 1982 to 1984. In addition, the papers contain conference proceedings stemming from Weinstein's service as vice-chairman of the American delegation to a major UNESCO (United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization) conference in Mexico City in 1982.
Democracy.; Espionage, Russian--United States.; Hiss, Alger.; Chambers, Whittaker.; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953.; Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953.; John Paul II, Pope, 1920-2005--Assassination attempt, 1981.
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Correspondence, 1981-1983
    - A-E (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - F-J (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - K-O (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - P-T (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - U-Z (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Current business, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Articles to be commissioned, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Articles, correspondence, memoranda, galley proofs, and reports, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 1: 8-11)
  - Articles and galley proofs, 1983 (Box-folder 2: 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Fall issue suggestions, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - To be commissioned, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Current business, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Staff action to be taken, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Meeting, 1982 November 12 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Articles and correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Current business, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Special edition, 1983 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Urgent business, 1981 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Current business, 1983 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Reprinted articles, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Working group, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 3: 10)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - "A Response to Robert Sherrill," typescript, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - "What the Hiss Files Show," typescript, undated (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - "Opening the FBI's Hiss and Rosenberg Files: No 'Smoking Gun' (but Many Powder Burns)," typescript, undated (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - "The Alger Hiss Case Revisited," printed copy, 1971 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - "The Symbolism of Subversion: Notes on Some Cold War Icons," printed copy, 1972 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Replies to critics, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 4: 6-7)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Henderson, Nicholas, 1975 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Henderson, Loy, 1975 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Cross, Claude, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Donegan, Thomas, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Field, Hermann, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Cantwell, Robert, 1951-1977 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Capers, Roberta, 1975 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Clubb, O. Edmund, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Appell, Donald T., 1974 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Shemitz, Reuben and Alice, 1975 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Hiss, Anthony, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Kaplan, Karel, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 4: 19)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - Second response to Stephen S. Salant, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
  - Press coverage of New York Review of Books article, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 3-4)
  - Correspondence relating to publications, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 5: 5)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Schapiro, Meyer, 1924-1961 (Box-folder 5: 6-7)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes photocopies of correspondence from Whittaker Chambers.
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1938-1949 (Box-folder 5: 8-9)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1948-1973 (Box-folder 5: 10-11)
  - Time investigators, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Hiss Alger, 1949-1977 (Box-folder 6: 2-8)
  - Silvermaster, Nathan Gregory, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
  - Inslerman, Felix August, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Hiss, Donald, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Miscellany, 1948-1977 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Yale University Library, 1972 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - "The Trial of Alger Hiss," typescript, 1949 (Box-folder 7: 7-10)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - Correspondence and notes regarding Perjury, 1978 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Perjury, typescript, 1978 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Perjury, typescript, 1978 (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1948-1978 (Box-folder 8: 3-5)
  - U.S. Department of Justice, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Hellman-Trilling controversy, 1976 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 8: 9-11)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Rubens, Ruth Marie, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1948-1977 (Box-folder 9: 3-7)
  - Mundt, Karl E., 1949-1950 (Box-folder 9: 8-9)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - McSweeney, Thomas G., "The Unintended Consequences of Political Reform," doctoral thesis, undated (Box-folder 10: 1-6)
  - Printed matter, 1981 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Clippings, 1982 (Box-folder 10: 8)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Article, correspondence, and reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - European trip, 1983 (Box-folder 11: 2)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) Working Group on International Communications Policy materials
  - Articles and transcript of proceedings, 1952-1981 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Correspondence and reports, 1981 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Clippings, notes, and reports, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - New World Information Order, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and reports, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Notes, printed matter, and reports, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 12: 2)
- National Endowment for Democracy materials
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1984 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Incoming proposals and grant guidelines, 1984 (Box-folder 12: 4)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Correspondence and reports, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Appointment book, 1982 (Box-folder 12: 7)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) Working Group on International Communications Policy materials
  - Clippings, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Media Institute, 1981 (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - Voice of America/Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 12: 10)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Editor's page, 1982 Winter (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - European neutrality, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Article, correspondence, and reports, 1982 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Correspondence, notes, reports, speech, and statement, 1982 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Articles, clippings, correspondence, and memoranda, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Clippings, correspondence, and memoranda, 1981 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - UNESCO, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 13: 7-8)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Fundraising, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 14: 2-4)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, notes, and reports, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Roundtable meetings, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and study, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Agendas, article, correspondence, mailing lists, memoranda, paper, and programs, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Production, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 1-3)
  - Interns, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Bills, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Central America, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 6-9)
    Materials relating to a trip made by Allen Weinstein to Nicaragua and El Salvador, as part of an American delegation of journalists.
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Current business, 1982 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Current business, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Urgent business, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 4)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Correspondence, curriculum vitae, notes, and writings, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Clippings, correspondence, and writings, 1967 (Box-folder 16: 6)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) study of the International Telecommunications Union materials
  - General, 1984 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Draft of study, 1984 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Miscellaneous documents, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - Miscellaneous articles, clippings, and book excerpts, 1951-1972 (Box-folder 17: 4)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - Notes and memorandum, 1977 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Article on Freedom of Information Act, ca. 1975 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Photographs used in Perjury, 1978 (Box-folder 17: 7)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Peter, Joszef (Alexander Stevens), 1939-1949 (Box-folder 18: 1-4)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation reports on Hiss case, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 18: 5-9)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation reports on Hiss case, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
  - Reno, Franklin Vincent, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 19: 3-4)
  - Reno, Philip, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - Pigman, William Ward, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Bullitt, William C., 1949-1950 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - Browder, Earl, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - Fischer, Louis, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - Burck, Jacob, 1975 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - Herrmann, John Theodore, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - Silverman, Abraham George, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - Sola, Ralph de, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Solow, Herbert, 1938-1965 (Box-folder 19: 15)
  - Schmahl, Horace, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 19: 16)
  - Samuel, Rinna, 1975 (Box-folder 19: 17)
  - Sayre, Francis Bowes, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 19: 18)
  - Pressman, Lee, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 19: 19)
  - Peters, Paul, 1948-1974 (Box-folder 19: 20)
  - Unanswered questions, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Peter, Joszef, 1933-1951 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Pigman, William Ward, 1948 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Cronin, John F., 1946 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - "Pumpkin Papers,", 1938-1952 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Garlin, Sendor, 1949 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Hiss trial, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Rosen, William, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Clippings and serial issues relating to Alger Hiss, 1962-1976 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - Documents used, 1950-1976 (Box-folder 20: 10-11)
  - Forgery thesis, 1940-1957 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - Files cited, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Westminster farm purchase, 1936-1962 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Herbst, Josephine, 1934-1968 (Box-folder 21: 3-6)
  - Solow, Herbert, and Meyer A. Zeligs, 1962 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Schmahl, Horace, 1941-1974 (Box-folder 21: 8-9)
  - Sayre, Francis B., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Silverman, Abraham George, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 21: 11)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Soviet espionage, 1945-1955 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1946-1950 (Box-folder 22: 2-4)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1929-1973 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - Field, Frederick Vanderbilt, 1949 (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Field, Noel and Herta, 1949-1977 (Box-folder 22: 7)
  - Halsey, Margaret, 1951 (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - Browder, Earl, 1939-1948 (Box-folder 22: 9)
  - Barnes, Joseph, 1949 (Box-folder 22: 10)
  - Binger, Carl, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 22: 11)
  - Berle, Adolph, 1948-1975 (Box-folder 22: 12)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1949-1976 (Box-folder 22: 13)
  - Cooke, Alistair, 1950-1957 (Box-folder 22: 14)
  - Collins, Henry, 1948-1954 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1933-1948 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1924-1976 (Box-folder 23: 3-11)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1936-1976 (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1942-1950 (Box-folder 24: 3)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - Article on Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, 1975 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Perjury, typescript, 1977 (Box-folder 24: 5-8)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Davis, John F., 1948-1976 (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - Currie, Lauchlin, 1951 (Box-folder 24: 10)
  - Fansler, Roberta, 1949 (Box-folder 24: 11)
  - Fahy, Charles, 1948 (Box-folder 24: 12)
  - Freeman, Joseph, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 24: 13)
  - Crane, William Edward, 1949 (Box-folder 24: 14)
  - Hiss, Priscilla, 1949 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1935-1976 (Box-folder 25: 2-6)
  - Hiss, Donald, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - Buttenweisser, Helen L., 1957-1976 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - Jowitt, the Earl, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Rubens, Arnold and Ruth Marie, 1938-1949 (Box-folder 25: 10)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1948-1961 (Box-folder 25: 11-12)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - UNESCO conference, 1982 (Box-folder 26: 1-8)
  - Memorandum, paper, and printed matter, 1981 (Box-folder 26: 9)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, and statement, 1983 (Box-folder 26: 10-11)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and papers, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Printed matter, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 27: 2-3)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Bulletins, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 5-6)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Correspondence and memorandum, 1982 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - UNESCO conference, 1982 (Box-folder 27: 8-10)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Correspondence, papers, and proposal, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Reports, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Newsletter, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 4)
  - Correspondence and résumés, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 5)
  - Correspondence and printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 6)
  - Report, statements, and transcripts, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 7)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  - Reports, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Socialist International, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 3-5)
  - Research project, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 29: 6-9)
  - Research project, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 30: 1-3)
  - Manatt, Charles T., 1982 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - Inventory, 1983 (Box-folder 30: 5-6)
  - Institute for Democracy, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Conference papers, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Conference proceedings, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - Calendar, clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 30: 10)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Correspondence and invitations, 1983 (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 31: 3)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1983 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Bipartisan study, 1983 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Xeroxing, 1983 (Box-folder 31: 6-7)
  - Proposals, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 31: 8)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 31: 9-10)
  - Printed matter, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Articles of incorporation, bill, and report, 1983 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - International communications, 1983 (Box-folder 32: 3-4)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Address and paper, 1983 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 32: 7-10)
  - Interim report, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 33: 2)
  - Bonn, West Germany, 1983 (Box-folder 33: 3)
  - Executive board, 1983 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Proposal, 1983 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - Nominations, 1983 (Box-folder 33: 6)
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 33: 7)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1983 (Box-folder 33: 8-10)
  - Europe/Tashkent trip, 1983 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Intergovernmental Council of the International Programme for the Development of Communication (IPDC), 1982-1983 (Box-folder 34: 2-6)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 34: 7-9)
  - Report, 1983 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - Budget, 1983 (Box-folder 35: 2)
  - Finances, 1983 (Box-folder 35: 3)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 35: 4)
  - Advisory panel, 1982 (Box-folder 35: 5)
  - Trip to West Germany, 1983 (Box-folder 35: 6)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, papers, and reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 35: 7-10)
- National Endowment for Democracy materials
  - Incorporation, 1983 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - White House, 1983 (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - Invitations, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 36: 3)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, proposals, and reports, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 36: 4-9)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Speeches by Jeane J. Kirkpatrick, 1984 (Box-folder 36: 10)
  - Clippings, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 36: 11)
  - Printed matter, 1981 (Box-folder 36: 12)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Hiss, Alger, 1942-1975 (Box-folder 37: 1-10)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - UNESCO conference, 1982 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 38: 2)
  - Conference on Free Elections, 1982 (Box-folder 38: 3)
  - Circulation, 1979 (Box-folder 38: 4)
  - Articles, correspondence, and memoranda, 1982 (Box-folder 38: 5-8)
  - American Political Foundation, 1980 (Box-folder 38: 9)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Proposal, 1982 (Box-folder 38: 10)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1982 (Box-folder 38: 11)
  - Open Forum speech, 1982 (Box-folder 38: 12)
  - Memoranda, 1982 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Résumés, 1982 (Box-folder 39: 2-3)
  - State Department cable, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Weddington, Sarah, 1982 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Offices, 1982 (Box-folder 39: 6)
  - Consultants, 1982 (Box-folder 39: 7-8)
  - Vojvoda, Robert B., Mr. and Mrs., 1982 (Box-folder 39: 9)
  - Stationery design, 1982 (Box-folder 39: 10)
  - Executive board, 1982 (Box-folder 39: 11)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 39: 12-14)
  - Current business, 1983 (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
  - Strasbourg Conference on Parliamentary Democracy, 1983 (Box-folder 40: 3)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 40: 4)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Résumés, 1983 (Box-folder 40: 5)
  - Report on elections, undated (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - Ad Hoc Citizens Committee for the Madrid-Helsinki Review Meeting, 1980 (Box-folder 40: 7)
  - U.S. National Commission for UNESCO meeting, 1984 December 13 (Box-folder 40: 8)
  - Printed matter, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 40: 9-10)
  - Washington Post, 1981 (Box-folder 40: 11)
  - Presidential inaugural, 1985 (Box-folder 40: 12)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - Interviews regarding Perjury, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Correspondence concerning Perjury, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - Reviews of Perjury, 1978 (Box-folder 41: 3-10)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1948-1976 (Box-folder 42: 1-9)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1942-1976 (Box-folder 43: 1-4)
  - Hiss, Priscilla, 1949-1975 (Box-folder 43: 5)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1949 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  - Hiss, Alger, and Whittaker Chambers, 1949-1975 (Box-folder 43: 7)
  - Pressman, Ann and Sophia, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 43: 8)
  - Pickett, Clarence, 1948 (Box-folder 43: 9)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1942-1949 (Box-folder 43: 10)
  - McDowell, David, 1952-1964 (Box-folder 43: 11)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Hate mail, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 44: 2)
  - Clippings, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 44: 3)
  - Printed matter, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 44: 4)
  - Timmerman, Jacobo, 1982 (Box-folder 44: 5)
  - Latin America, 1982 (Box-folder 44: 6)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 44: 7-9)
  - Background material, 1983 (Box-folder 44: 10)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, paper, and proposals, 1983 (Box-folder 45: 1-2)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 45: 3-6)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - State of democracy file, 1983 (Box-folder 46: 1-2)
  - Costa Rica, 1983 (Box-folder 46: 3-7)
  - Briefings, 1983 (Box-folder 46: 8)
  - Background material, 1983 (Box-folder 46: 9)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 46: 10)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Central American trip, 1982 (Box-folder 47: 1)
  - UNESCO conference
    - Book publishers, 1982 (Box-folder 47: 2-3)